<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Game of Life</string>
    <string name="speed">Speed: </string>
    <string name="delete">DELETE</string>
    <string name="size">Size</string>
    <string name="generations">Generations:</string>
    <string name="about">About Game of Life</string>
    <string name="load">Load Saved Game</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="genpersec">gen/sec</string>
    <string name="survivalRules">Survival Rules</string>
    <string name="toroidal_world">Toroidal World (aka Infinite)</string>
    <string name="next_gen_visible">Next Generation Visible</string>
    <string name="mark_cells_for_death">Mark cells that will die in the next generation</string>
    <string name="creation_rules">Creation Rules</string>
    <string name="title_activity_about_game_of_life">About Game Of Life</string>
    <string name="doyouevencode">Do you even code, bruh?</string>
    <string name="aboutthisapp">About this app</string>
    <string name="title_activity_preferences">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_saved_state_list">Load Saved Game</string>
    <string name="title_activity_do_you_code">Open Source!</string>
    <string name="attribution">Attribution</string>
    <string name="title_activitiy_about_this_app">About this App</string>
    <string name="title_activity_attribution">Attributions</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="toroidal_summary">Makes the world infinite (kind of). Cells on the right edge will neighbour with cells on the left. Same for top and bottom edges.</string>
    <string name="next_gen_summary">Make new cells that will be created in the coming generation visible in current generation.</string>
    <string name="mark_for_death_summary">Cells that will not make it into the next generation will be marked with a black X.</string>
    <string name="creation_summary">Number of neighbours an empty spot needs for a new cell to be born there next generation.</string>
    <string name="survival_summary">Number of neighbours a living cell needs to have in order to survive into the next generation.</string>
    <string name="save_title">How shalteth I calleth thee patternst?"</string>
    <string name="save_title_hint">(Pick a save name)</string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>

    <string name="game_of_life_explanation">The Game of Life is a cellular automation that was created by British
        mathematician John Conway in 1970. The word \"game\" is used loosely here. It\'s a mathematical model of cellular
        life. Cells live, reproduce and die according to simple rules.. not unlike humans.\n\n
Da Rulz:\n
 - With the original rules, if a cell has 2 or 3 neighbours it can survive into the next generation, otherwise death awaits.\n
        "   (If a cell has less than 2 neighbours it dies of loneliness, and if it has more than 3 it dies of overpopulation.)\n
 - If an empty space has exactly 3 neighbours than in the next generation a new baby cell will be born.\n\n
(Baby cells are exactly like adult cells - I just threw in the word \'baby\' there for fun. This is what counts as fun for me.)\n\n
That\'s it, 2 simple rules and a world of complexity. It\'s been studied a lot since then and grown quite popular among
        mathematicians, numberphiles and math nerds such as myself. It\'s also popularly given as an assignment in computer
        programming classes - which is good news for you cheaty-cheaters out there because the code for this app is open source.
        (Don\'t cheat! Think of the kittens!)\n\n

Lots of people like to play with the rules to see what happens when you change the number of cells needed to survive,
        or to create new life. You are free to experiment here all you like - in the settings page there\'s an option
        to choose the rules and experiment.\n\n

Want to know more?  Check out the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_Game_of_Life">wikipedia page</a> on
        your local interweb.\n\n</string>

    <string name="do_you_code_text">Do you like the app but think it\'s missing that one feature you just wish it had?\n
    Do you wish you could add a few settings or tweak the sinfully ugly UI and make it purdy?\n
    Or do you just want to take a look at the central algorithm and see what I done did there?\n\n
    Do you even code, bruh?\n\n

        It\'s all open source so if you\'re interested in messing around with or improving the source code check out the
        <a href="https://github.com/heslihop/game-of-life---Android">github page</a>\n\n

        This app is still in the early stages but is always planned to be free and without ads. It\'s my first app and was mostly built
        just for fun and to learn. I welcome comments and constructive criticism, especially from programmers who have seen
        (and winced at) the source code.\n\n

    Cheers!\n\n</string>

    <string name="attribution_text">Only one of the background pics used requires attribution. It\'s the microbial handprint.
    That picture is reproduced here with permission from: Tasha Sturm © @ Cabrillo College.\n
    \"Bacterial handprint of an 8 year old boy after being outside.  Mainly normal flora and environmental bacteria most of which
        is not harmful to a health person.\"\n\n

    The other background pictures don\'t require attribution and were taken from pixabay.com and unsplash.com. Both sites are
        great sources for stock photos provided by their userbase.\n\n

     As this project is opensource, recognition will also be given here to any developers that add to the development of
        future versions.</string>

    <string name="about_this_app_text">This app was initially created by one person but has since been made open source
    so everyone can contribute to creating the changes and improvements they want to see. This is first app. A lot of people
    code The Game of Life when they\'re learning to program and this is my version.\n\n

    If you\'ve never heard of John Conway\'s Game of Life check out the "About Game of Life" in the main menu. To answer
    questions specifically about this app I\'ve created a FAQ:\n\n

    Q. What do all the buttons do?\n
    A. They should all be easy to figure out by pressing on them. The only one that is not obvious is the \'redo\' button.
    That one reloads either the last time the board was randomized, or the last load of a save file - whichever came latest.\n\n

    Q. Why do you let the cells go on top of the UI?! It\'s driving my OCD crazy.\n
    A. This is actually a metaphor for life. Especially bacterial life. Bacteria go over everything. Life goes over everything.
    It\'s not easily restricted and bounded. It overflows.\n\n

    Q. Why did you use custom images for the randomize and hide buttons, but left everything else as standard images? It
    looks disjointed, like you gave up half way through.\n
    A. To the untrained eye, that\'s exactly what it might look like. And someone watching me program might come to the same
    conclusion. Actually, randomize and hide-all don\'t have well known symbols so I needed to create my own. I also thought
    the disjointed look created another metaphor for life. It\'s chaotic.\n\n

    Q. Why isn\'t there any clear instructions as to how the game works? You just throw the player in, and even if they make
    it to the main menu, there\'s no option for instructions.\n
    A. Life also has no instructions. We are thrown into the world to figure it out on our own. Since we are creatures that
    evolved in environments like this over hundreds of millions of years, I expect you come equipped with the skills to
        figure out my app.\n\n

    Q. In that last answer you mentioned evolution. That\'s highly offensive to those of us who don\'t believe in evolution.
    How dare you?\n
    A. Whether you were fabricated over hundreds of millions of years by evolution, or created in an instant by an act of
        divinity, you should be well equipped to handle my app without instructions. No one needs to be offended today.
        Not on my watch.\n\n

    Q. Are you just rambling nonsense because you ran out of questions to ask yourself and then answer?\n
    A. Indubitably.\n\n

    Q. My question wasn\'t answered. What do I do?\n
    A. Head on over to github (See \'Do you even Code, bruh?\') and add the question to this FAQ, along with the answer.\n\n
    </string>

    <string-array name="pref_creation_rules_options">
        <item>0</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pref_creation_rules_values">
        <item>0</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pref_creation_rules_defaults">
        <item>3</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pref_survival_rules_options">
        <item>0</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pref_survival_rules_values">
        <item>0</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pref_survival_rules_defaults">
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
